I just spent
6 days working
on it creating
like a small
MVP and now
we are close
to 37k of
monthly working Revenue
how does this
guy make over
$400,000 a year
with an app
he built in
just 6 days
Well turns out
he really knows
how to find
customers obviously there
is which is
always a big
one for this
kind of products
I was able
to get quite
a lot of
users pretty fast
thanks to this
Julian Nom started
his journey while
working a 9
to-5 as a
software engineer I
was commuting 3
hours day I
was spending all
of this commute
time on my
computer working on
the side projects
after years of
experimenting with different
side projects Julian
finally found an
idea that worked
and now he's
a solopreneur making
a doctor's salary
while working on
multiple passion projects
so I gave
Julian a call
to ask him
exactly how he
did it and
how anyone else
can do something
similar luckily he
shared a ton
of good stuff
how to find
and validate ideas
the best places
to Market a
new product and
the viral Loop
strategy that got
Julian to over
$400,000 a year
all right let's
get into it
I'm Pat walls
and this is
starter [Music]
story all right
welcome Julian it's
nice to have
you tell me
a little about
who you are
and what you
built okay I'm
Julian I'm 28
I'm the founder
of not forms
which is a
form builder for
notion users we
have close to
100K registered users
and now we
are close to
37k of monthly
working of you
got it can
you tell us
a little bit
more about the
story of how
you found the
idea for note
forms yeah definitely
I was a
notion user for
maybe two or
3 years I
really love the
product and one
day notion finally
released their IPI
which meant that
anyone could build
Integrations and product
one notion and
I just decided
to copy a
feature that another
database like product
named air table
had which were
forms so you
know I just
spent 6 days
working on it
creating like a
small MVP timeing
was important uh
and it really
helped going the
project it's fine
to start small
as soon as
you get some
users and some
feedback you're able
to iterate much
faster and to
focus on the
you know core
value of whatever
you're building so
you built your
SAS around an
already existing platform
notion why do
you like this
approach better than
doing a traditional
Standalone
SAS building a
one platform is
easier you don't
have to build
the community around
it you can
kind of cannibalize
part of it
and try to
solve a sub
issue which is
kind of what
I did with
not forms right
notion already had
a huge Community
people were really
fan of the
products they had
like a huge
sub rect tons
of Facebook group
of course it
comes with its
own set of
issues you have
the platform risk
but I think
finding this kind
of platforms it's
really a good
way to to
start okay so
you've already built
a couple profitable
projects now are
there any other
methods you have
to finding winning
ideas yeah I
think the easiest
way to to
find ideas is
try to solve
your own problems
if you're your
own user then
it's definitely easier
to build a
great product if
you use it
you get to
see the flows
and the issues
and improve on
them the drawback
of this is
that sometimes you
can have a
problem and think
it's great to
build a tool
for this but
then you realize
you're the only
person with that
problem because of
that I think
it's important to
ship fast and
try and put
it in front
of other people
to get some
feedback early other
ways to get
some ideas I
guess is just
to be curious
talk to people
for instance I
really love you
know with my
friends that have
totally different career
paths and talk
about like the
way they work
their process their
daily lives and
it's always amazing
to me uh
with a technical
background to hear
that you know
sometimes they spend
one two 3
hours every day
doing something that
could easily be
automated also being
on social medias
like Twitter I
think is really
a great way
you hear about
new tech you
hear about New
Opportunities you discover
new things that
later you can
apply to new
problems I think
that's also a
great way all
right so once
you have an
idea in mind
what's your process
for validating the
idea and know
that it's something
that's actually worth
building yeah so
my way of
doing things is
just to actually
build a product
or at least
an MVP for
it and then
share it to
as many people
as I can
and get instantly
some feedback from
the users focusing
on a project
for a small
short amount of
time really helps
you get a
sense of whether
this is valuable
or not of
course it's hard
to apply to
many projects you
know like there
are things that
you cannot just
build in one
week as as
I'm a solopreneur
you know like
I try to
avoid this and
focus on things
that I can
build by myself
and quickly the
more you build
I think the
faster it is
to build now
you know like
every time I'm
starting a new
project I can
just copy the
code base from
the previous project
keep all the
UI and that
kind of things
and I can
just focus on
the core logic
and the value
that I want
to bring to
the users so
you get faster
every time my
favorite part about
Julian's story is
he was building
side projects while
he kept his
full-time job and
just like Julian
I actually did
this same thing
I started a
million-dollar business while
I was working
in 9 to5
and it wasn't
easy it required
working on the
right idea getting
tons of feedback
and actually figuring
out how to
monetize so I
could replace my
9 to-5 income
but the hardest
part above all
consistency actually showing
up every day
and doing the
work that's why
we created the
academy it's a
5we program where
you'll find an
idea build it
launch it validate
it all while
working just 2
hours a day
it's the same
framework I use
to build a
million-dollar business and
it's what I've
seen thousands of
successful Founders actually
use it's what
actually works because
it's all about
taking action and
actually building which
is what I
want to see
you really take
a shot at
so if you're
curious about building
a profitable side
project like Julian
and me and
you still feel
like you don't
have the time
to work on
it or work
on your ideas
well head to
the first link
in the description
if you want
to learn more
okay so you
believe in shipping
fast fast but
do you have
any Frameworks on
how to build
MVPs really quickly
the best way
of doing that
as a technical
person is to
focus on the
product and not
on the technology
I've been using
the exact same
stack for the
past 10 years
pretty much since
I started coding
I'm actually using
PHP which a
lot of developer
likes to make
fun of with
this PHP framework
called laravel and
now I'm super
pro efficient with
it I have
ton of you
know small piece
of code that
can reuse from
one project to
the other and
that really saves
ton of time
so yeah you
can spend some
times if you
have fun learning
about Technologies but
if you want
to build projects
just do it
as fast as
you can use
what you know
and focus on
that okay cool
now let's talk
about marketing yeah
how did you
get users for
your app and
what are the
best places right
now for people
to find customers
I published the
projects and then
I just spammed
all the notion
related communities I
could find online
obviously there is
Reddit which is
always a big
one for this
kind of products
usually they have
you know like
a subreddit dedicated
to it people
that are really
fond of the
product so they're
curious about discovering
new things around
it usually people
on Reddit and
and these kind
of communities that
really don't like
people putting links
there trying to
get some new
users but because
it was so
new and because
the product was
entirely free there
there's not even
monetization in it
I feel like
they were kind
of okay with
me doing that
and that really
helped you know
like I was
able to get
quite a lot
of users pretty
fast thanks to
this but also
another platform I
found to be
super useful our
Facebook groups there
are many people
using Facebook and
Facebook groups are
super alive there
are Facebook groups
for everything like
for your C
for sports for
apps for whatever
and that was
super useful as
well Twitter I
mean is great
the only thing
with Twitter is
there is a
cold start issue
when you start
twitting you're basically
on your own
something really important
into getting started
on Twitter is
to find the
people that you
relate to so
the people that
inspire you and
to try and
interact with them
genu with times
they're going to
start you know
recognizing your face
they will interact
with you as
well you gain
some more followers
and you know
that's how you
get started product
I think is
a nice way
of advertising your
product but I
think it's a
bit overrated I
see some people
spending weeks preparing
for product launch
while in the
end you just
get a bit
of traffic a
nice backlink and
that's pretty much
it like when
I did the
launch for not
forms I got
you know like
of course more
eyes on the
products but I
think I didn't
get a single
sale from the
from the launch
you know that's
my experience with
it I see
okay tell us
now about your
special growth strategy
and how someone
can implement it
in their business
to get more
users today as
people starting using
it they were
building forms with
notion forms and
they were sharing
the forms because
you know that's
the purpose of
a form Builder
you build a
form and then
you share it
you embed it
on your website
and because of
this people that
are supposed to
F the form
they get to
see what you
built it's easy
for you to
just add a
link back to
your product or
do some kind
of advertisement and
that becomes viral
because the more
users you have
the more people
see your product
and then the
more users you
have so I
think if you
have a product
for almost every
product you can
find a way
of incentivizing your
users to share
your product or
piece of your
product so it
could be you
know just a
small widget that
you can put
on your website
that's exactly what
does product hunt
by the way
you know like
they give you
this little badge
to say hey
I was product
of the day
and then you
put this on
your website and
then it's a
it's a back
Ling for product
so if you
can find a
smart way of
doing this or
make it valuable
for your users
to share what
they did on
your platform then
you can create
a viral Loop
and I think
that's super important
to try and
build something like
this awesome but
with all these
users coming in
how do you
manage customer support
or all these
customer inquiries so
for the first
year working on
it I was
entirely alone on
the project so
I was doing
everything myself I
was receiving messages
like all the
time at night
so sometimes I
would forget you
know to turn
off notifications and
then it would
wake me up
later on I
I hired someone
to to help
me with this
and that was
really relief but
that being said
I really don't
regret uh doing
this that way
it really helped
me build a
better products understand
the user needs
but also identify
issues within the
product so even
today we still
have the operator
you like an
agent that's working
with me that's
uh always on
it and we
also have an
AI chat bot
that we train
you know on
all the product
docks and and
all the past
conversations and really
incentivize people to
talk to us
so within the
product we have
tons of button
you know they
can click to
report a bug
leave us some
feedback suggest a
feature or just
you know like
talk to us
really since the
beginning I've only
Built what people
ask me to
build nice so
actively talking to
customers is how
you actually find
the features to
add let's now
talk about monetization
how did you
start making money
from note forms
how did you
make your first
dollar yeah it's
starting taking off
slowly I think
at some point
I which th000
users I had
tons of feature
requests all of
these features that
I was adding
you know a
little Pro tag
and when you
clicked on it
it says ahey
this is free
for now because
it's the beta
but whenever it
will launch it
will become a
paid feature and
then one day
I built all
the subscription system
and I just
flipped the switch
and I told
all the users
hey now this
part of the
product is paid
since you were
there since the
beginning here's a
4% discount code
that you can
use uh for
life and it
was a long
day I remember
I was just
you know like
refreshing the STP
page to try
and get a
a new subscription
but nothing came
and then later
during the night
one guy took
a a yearly
subscription even and
I was so
happy like I
made $90 and
then the day
after maybe I
got two and
then three and
then I didn't
get any subscription
for like 3
days started to
panic and then
I got another
one and just
went on from
there okay now
let's talk about
pricing how did
you decide on
the pricing for
your product yeah
pricing is super
hard you don't
want to be
too expensive but
of course you
want to make
as much money
as you can
so I didn't
know what to
do so I
just looked at
all the for
Builders out there
and I thought
you know hey
like this is
a new product
I have one10
of all the
features they offer
so I need
to be cheaper
than all of
them and then
over time I
just experimented a
bit I tried
you know increasing
the price slightly
I saw that
it didn't really
have any impact
on the conversion
so I did
it again and
then later on
I also added
some more expensive
plans that also
helped you know
increasing a bit
the revenue and
further let's talk
about business model
how did you
choose between a
one-time payment and
a subscription
if it makes
sense for a
product to have
a subscription then
it's definitely a
good idea because
getting recing revenue
is amazing because
you can you
know acquire customer
and then for
the next X
months you will
get money for
it and I
found that selling
something for $50
per month is
much easier than
selling one thing
for $500 one
time okay let's
talk about AI
are you currently
using it in
your business overall
I'm super excited
about it there
was very recently
hype about um
a new developer
tool called cursor
which is kind
of an AI
P IDE and
I recently started
using it and
honestly I'm I'm
amazed and it's
literally like speeding
up by maybe
two uh my
work nowadays with
all the content
you can find
online with tools
like AI I
think it's easier
than ever to
build a product
on your own
and you know
to start working
on something so
that's amazing and
I'm so glad
you know I'm
living in this
period of time
because there are
just so many
possibilities and I'm
super excited about
all of this
okay that's awesome
on the topic
of technology what
are some other
software tools you're
using to profitably
run your business
for the Tex
tack so the
back end framework
is a PHP
framework named laravel
the front end
is built with
a view framework
name next it's
all the pages
and make sure
that everything loads
fast the database
is post gr
SQL we host
everything on AWS
so of course
you know since
I work there
for a bit
it's just easier
for me that
way now we
Ed for subscription
billing we use
amplitude to track
product analytics you
know like the
user behavior on
the platform what
they use that
kind of things
we use crisp
for the support
chat we use
Sentry you know
to track uh
the errors that
happens on the
app so that
we can you
know like learn
about them and
fix them we
use a product
called feature base
for a road
map like a
public road map
where people can
see you know
what's going to
be built next
and of course
feature request and
Bug reports with
three people fulltime
and one person
that's parttime so
the total salary
for them is
5K so that
excludes me then
there is 1K
that we pay
for servers and
all the SAS
tools that I
mentioned earlier we
spend around 3K
per month on
ads uh so
we only do
Google ads mostly
because I don't
know how to
do anything else
and then usually
we spend probably
like around 2K
per month with
random Freelancers so
it could be
you like UI
designers
copywriters Sometimes some
external developers that
kind of thing
okay now last
question that we
ask all founders
we interview if
you could sit
on younger Julian's
shoulder and give
him some advice
when he was
just starting out
what would you
say um Amazon
has a set
of leadership principles
one of them
is bios for
action and I
think that's a
really good one
the most important
thing you can
do is start
if you spend
too much time
thinking about it
and not doing
anything that at
some point you'll
just get demotivated
and and nothing's
going to happen
the Project's going
to die but
as soon as
you know you
start working on
it and you
get you know
to see the
first results get
the first users
it really FS
your motivation and
of course it
helps you shavee
the product better
because you get
feedback and and
so on so
the first thing
would definitely be
launch as soon
as you as
you can don't
overthink it don't
build too many
features just build
a simple MVP
and then put
it in front
of the eyes
of your customers
the other thing
is not to
be shy so
that took me
a bit of
time as well
but try to
talk about it
to as many
people as you
can you can
only know if
it's a good
idea or if
it's valuable or
if it's actually
useful uh by
getting the opinion
of other people
no one is
going to stop
everything they do
in their life
just to build
what you describe
them right if
that happens that
means that you
know one guy
was more motivated
than you by
your own ID
and that's on
you right you
should have done
it in the
end you're not
risking that much
I think if
if if you
know you can
find a job
especially like if
you're software engineer
six months off
working on a
project is is
nothing the risk
seems huge but
I think it's
not that big
all right Julian
thank you thanks
for coming on
and sharing your
story I love
the business that
you built and
wishing you luck
in the future
keep sharing your
story awesome cool
thanks man yo
guys I really
hope you all
enjoyed the video
and wrote down
some good takeaways
that Julian shared
but I do
want to say
something real quick
at the end
of the day
the point of
these videos is
to inspire you
and show you
how other people
just like you
found ideas and
built them hopefully
this inspires you
to go out
and do this
thing on your
own while learning
is important taking
action is the
thing that's actually
going to get
you that dream
outcome if you
still feel like
you're struggling to
take action no
matter what then
I highly recommend
you check out
the starter story
Academy it's a
5-we program where
you'll come up
with an idea
you'll build it
you'll launch it
you'll validate it
and you'll get
it in front
of customers what's
even more amazing
is you'll do
this alongside hundreds
of other people
doing the same
thing building something
that will change
their life and
we will hold
you accountable every
single day to
showing up and
doing the work
the academy is
what I wish
I had when
I was getting
started and I
still had a
full-time job and
it's designed for
you to actually
build something that
changes your life
just head to
the first link
in the description
and I'll give
you a bunch
of more info
about it I
hope to see
you in there
otherwise I'll see
you in the
next one peace [Music]